hey everyone welcome to another lesson
in this task automation course today we
are going to talk about the execution
section in tosca
tosca helps you to execute your test
cases with the help of execution lists
now what's the difference between the
execution lists and what we have seen
earlier which was called the scratch
book
in scratchbook we used to individually
run our test cases but if you noticed
once you close the scratchbook all your
results are gone
so it's not an ideal
way of running your tests because you
require the results for
debugging or for generating your reports
or for historical purposes right
so execution less is the recommended way
of running your tests once they are
ready
let's see what are these execution lists
so it's nothing but it's a collection of
your test cases which are already ready
for execution
and all the results of these executions
are always stored in the execution list
so
if you are running your test cases
on different iterations right so there
are several iterations you want to run
your test cases all the iterations
whether past or field would be stored in
the execution list
once a test case is added to an
execution list it becomes an execution
entry
now there could be
different execution entries or that
could be execution entry folders
if you want to make some changes after
you have added your test cases to the
execution list you can do that in the
test cases section
and then you can go back to the
execution list and you can just
synchronize the execution list by the
test cases so that all the changes which
were made
should also be reflected in the
execution list
the best way to create an execution list
is by dragging and dropping a test case
or a test case folder to the execution
list that will create
the same folder structure which you have
in the test cases section
you can also do that manually by going
to the execution list and creating your
own folder structure
right so that all your tests are
organized as per your functionality or
as per your executions
so this is what execution list is all
about in tosca
let's see
how it looks like in tosca how you can
create an execution list how you can
actually run your execution list and how
the results are stored
so now i am back to tosca where we had
earlier created two template instances
of basically two test cases
from our template instance right
and now we want to execute this so you
can always go ahead and execute it from
the scratch book but the results are not
stored
so the other way is to go to the
execution list
now the execution list is the green
folder in tosca and if you don't see it
in your home page
then
what you can do is go to the section and
there you will find the execution okay
so
let me drag this
into the view so that we can see both
the test cases and the execution
now
as you can see under execution there are
some default folders
already created by tosca so that is the
execution list
which contains some standard module
examples which you can go ahead and run
it
or there are some virtual folders there
is also exploratory testing interactive
testing
and configurations and test events we'll
talk about test events later
but now we are concentrating on the
execution list right
so as i said
creating a execution list is pretty
simple
you can directly drag your test cases
folder or your individual test cases
into the execution list
now what i can do is i can create
a separate execution folder right or
execution list folder
inside this execution list this is to
just segregate my folder from the other
folders okay so let me call it the
source demo
right so this is my source demo
execution list entry folder
and inside this i want to have my test
cases okay
so what you can do
you can just drag it and you can drag it
to the source demo folder
now that will create an execution entry
list
which will have the actual log which
contains all the logs
after your test cases are run
and it will contain this test cases
folder
uh inside that will have the template
instance and inside that you will have
the test cases so basically the same
structure which you have in your test
cases the same will be created here
now it's better to
name this execution list right so i'll
just name it um
demo execution
you can name it anything you like
okay
so this is my execution
list entry which has been created here
containing my two test cases
the next thing is how to run them right
so
you can directly go to your execution
entry here and
right click and that will show you an
option called run now there is something
also called run as manual test case but
right now we are not focusing on that
so go ahead and run this
and you will see that now it will start
running
all the test cases which are present in
that execution enter list okay
so we have two test cases so it will be
running two test cases one after another
and then finally it will take us back to
the execution list where we can see all
our results from this execution okay
so now tosca is running our test cases
uh that's the first test case then it
will launch the second test case
and once it's done it will process the
results and show us
in the execution list
okay as you can see it is processing the
execution results and it has taken us
back to the execution
so let me bring this to center so that
we can see this clearly
so as you can see in the details section
you will find your execution details
okay now you can add or remove um any
columns here from the column chooser you
can find lots of other
um
other columns which you want to add here
which you can certainly add like um
summary or the
end time so that you have the duration
already how much time it took to
run this test case like what was the
start time
and some other details
and once you expand this you will see
that one test case was passed
and one was failed
right and it will show you the steps uh
what failed
and what passed
okay
so this is how you can execute your test
cases from the execution section in
execution list
and all the results would be stored
until you don't delete it or archive it
right so
whenever i come back here and i want to
see my results it will be present okay
so that's the advantage of execution
list and that's the recommended way of
running your test in real time